{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Riyadh","incorrectAnswers":["Mecca","Medina","Jeddah"],"question":"What is the capital of Saudi Arabia ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mickey Rourke","incorrectAnswers":["Idris Elba","Clark Gregg","Vin Diesel"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Ivan Vanko in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn","incorrectAnswers":["Henryk Sienkiewicz","Oscar Wilde","Ivan Turgenev"],"question":"Which author wrote 'One Day in the Life of Ivan Denisovich'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bruce Willis","incorrectAnswers":["Robert De Niro","Samuel L. Jackson","Liam Neeson"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Pulp Fiction and Sin City?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Quality never goes out of style","incorrectAnswers":["It's Style","Between love and madness lies obsession","Maybe she's born with it"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Levis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"King Kong ain’t got s*** on me!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"Well, nobody's perfect.\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Training Day'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Casting","incorrectAnswers":["Fishing","Baiting","Trolling"],"question":"What term, which refers to the selection of performers for a film, is also used to describe the process of fishermen catching fish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","South Korea","Thailand"],"question":"What country is the subject of the Shizuoka Shimbun and the Nikkan Ube Jiho newspapers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Whippersnapper","incorrectAnswers":["Salopettes","Cabotage","Bumfuzzle"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a young person considered to be presumptuous or overconfident'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Guinness ","incorrectAnswers":["Porters","Doogals","Old Black"],"question":"Which stout is Dublin world-famous for?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Microwaves","incorrectAnswers":["Ovens","Refrigerators","Dryers"],"question":"Which has longer wavelength?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gregor Mendel","incorrectAnswers":["James Clerk Maxwell","Albert Einstein","Enrico Fermi"],"question":"Which influential scientist and friar founded the modern science of genetics?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India ","incorrectAnswers":["Jamaica","France","The USA"],"question":"Which country does one associate 'Dum Aloo'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which musician wrote the song 'Knockin' on Heaven's Door'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brave New World","incorrectAnswers":["1984","Fahrenheit 451","The Handmaid's Tale"],"question":"In which dystopian novel are the terms 'Mother' and 'Father' forbidden?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Miller","incorrectAnswers":["William Johnson","Arnold Clark","Fred George"],"question":"Which US dramatist was once married to Marylin Monroe and penned the plays \"Death Of A Salesman\" and \"The Crucible\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Orange","White"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Ukraine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oil","incorrectAnswers":["Blood","Sperm","Water"],"question":"A 42 foot sperm whale has about 7 tons of __________ in it.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"On My Way","incorrectAnswers":["Oh My Word","Old Man Ways","Oh Man, Why"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'OMW' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pontius Pilate","incorrectAnswers":["Cesar Augustus","King Solomon","Judas"],"question":"Who presided over the trial of Jesus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Erinaceous","incorrectAnswers":["Sprunt","Whippersnapper","Frankenfood"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'of, pertaining to, or resembling a hedgehog'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Letitia Wright","incorrectAnswers":["Karen Gillan","Zendaya","Marisa Tomei"],"question":"The role of Shuri in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia ","incorrectAnswers":["China","Australia","Brazil"],"question":"Which Country Is The Largest?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A swarm","incorrectAnswers":["A host","A brace","A sedge"],"question":"What is the word for a group of bees?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"12 Drummers Drumming","incorrectAnswers":["12 Lords a Leaping","12 Maids a Milking","12 Swans a Swimming"],"question":"In the song \"The Twelve Days Of Christmas\", what did my true love give to me on the 12th day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Robbins","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Roth","Hugo Weaving","Timothy Spall"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including Mystic River and Top Gun?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Africa","Asia","North America"],"question":"Which continent has the largest rainforest area in the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2020","incorrectAnswers":["2019","2021","2018"],"question":"When was COVID-19 declared a Global Pandemic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Centigrade","incorrectAnswers":["Fahrenheit","Kelvin","Rankine"],"question":"What is the other name for the Celsius temperature scale, meaning \"divided into one hundred parts\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2005","incorrectAnswers":["2001","2009","2013"],"question":"In which year was the first video uploaded to YouTube?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Calf","incorrectAnswers":["A Caterpillar","A Larva","A Kid"],"question":"What is a baby rhinoceros known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Blue","White"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Belgium?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rita Coolidge","incorrectAnswers":["Louis Armstrong","Madonna","Billie Eilish"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film Octopussy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Kra–Dai","Turkic","Austronesian"],"question":"The language 'Sylheti' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Atlantic ","incorrectAnswers":["Pacific","Indian","Arctic"],"question":"In Which Ocean Is The Gulf Stream","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Antigua and Barbuda is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rachel Weisz","incorrectAnswers":["Salma Hayek","Catherine Deneuve","Audrey Hepburn"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in both The Favourite and The Mummy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George Washington","incorrectAnswers":["Winston Churchill","Alexander the Great","Lord Nelson"],"question":"Who was, \"First in war, first in peace and first in the hearts of his countrymen\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Celtics","incorrectAnswers":["Bruins","Marlins","Bellringers"],"question":"Basketball: The Boston ___________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Susan Sarandon","incorrectAnswers":["Kate Winslet","Helen Mirren","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Fame and Enchanted?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Yates","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Blur","Black Sabbath"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Abbey Road'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Banjul","incorrectAnswers":["Libreville","Accra","Paramaribo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Gambia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Orange","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Uruguay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pig ","incorrectAnswers":["Cow","Rabbit","Goat"],"question":"Boston butt and jowl are parts of a what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"NaHCO3","incorrectAnswers":["NaOCI","Hg","KNO3"],"question":"What is the chemical formula for sodium bicarbonate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Communists","incorrectAnswers":["The Socialists","The Liberals","The Fascists"],"question":"Which political party rose to power in China in 1949?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Iraq","Kazakhstan","Czechia"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Red with a green five-pointed star in the center.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Adagio","incorrectAnswers":["Allegro","Presto","Vivace"],"question":"Which musical term instructs a musician to play at a slow pace?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nahuatl","incorrectAnswers":["Mayan","Mixtec","Otomi"],"question":"What was the primary language of the Aztecs?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Green","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Israel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexander Pushkin","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Captain's Daughter'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"American Revolutionary War","incorrectAnswers":["American Civil War","World War I","World War II"],"question":"In the short story by Washington Irving, what war occurred while Rip Van Winkle was asleep?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blondie","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Call Me'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A paddling","incorrectAnswers":["A pack","A muster","A cete"],"question":"What is the word for a group of ducks?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1922","incorrectAnswers":["1860","1945","1818"],"question":"When was the Ottoman Empire officially dissolved?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Mughal Empire","incorrectAnswers":["The French Empire","The Aztec Empire","The Hittite Empire"],"question":"Which empire of the past had the \"Peacock Throne\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Trail of Tears","incorrectAnswers":["The Way of Woe","The Road of Ruin","The Path of Pain"],"question":"What was the most famous relocation by the Cherokee native Americans known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Marc Bolan","incorrectAnswers":["John Lennon","Jeff Buckley","Jimi Hendrix"],"question":"Which rockstar died when the Mini driven by his girlfriend crashed into a tree?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maroon with a white serrated band on the left side.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal horizontal bands of green white and red.","Three equal vertical bands of black yellow and red.","Three vertical bands of blue, yellow, and red."],"question":"What does the flag of Qatar look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Righteous Brothers","incorrectAnswers":["The Isley Brothers","Wham!","The Temptations"],"question":"Who Were Bobby Hatfield & Bill Medley?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"\"You can't have your cake and eat it too\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Waste not, want not\"","\"A penny saved is a penny earned\"","\"Actions speak louder than words\""],"question":"Which phrase is often used to mean that one cannot use something up and still have it available afterwards?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Sow","incorrectAnswers":["A Queen","A Ewe","A Gander"],"question":"What would you call a female guinea pig?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Severus Snape' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Niger","Rwanda","Taiwan"],"question":"Gujarati is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zimbabwe","incorrectAnswers":["Namibia","Malaysia","Belgium"],"question":"Harare is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nightwish","incorrectAnswers":["Haloo Helsinki!","Hanoi Rocks","Children of Bodom"],"question":"Which Finnish symphonic metal band released the album 'Oceanborn'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Frankfurt","incorrectAnswers":["Stockholm","Budapest","Prague"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dr. Bruce Banner","incorrectAnswers":["Karl Mordo","Odin","Ned Leeds"],"question":"Mark Ruffalo plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A simile","incorrectAnswers":["A metaphor","An analogy","A hyperbole"],"question":"What type of comparison is the phrase 'He was like an eagle chained to the ground' an example of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Asbestos","incorrectAnswers":["Bleach","Ethanol","Methadone"],"question":"Which substance takes its name from the Greek for `not flammable'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gone with the Wind","incorrectAnswers":["Downfall","My Neighbour Totoro","Up"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The daughter of a plantation owner conducts a romance with a roguish profiteer.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Disbar","incorrectAnswers":["Debrief","Devalue","Disown"],"question":"What is the term meaning to take away someone's license to practice law?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fiddle","incorrectAnswers":["Maraca","Gong","Bugle"],"question":"Which of these is a stringed instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"They call me Mister Tibbs!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"No wire hangers, ever!\"","\"King Kong ain’t got s*** on me!\"","\"As God is my witness, I'll never be hungry again.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'In the Heat of the Night'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The new European political order","incorrectAnswers":["Fossil fuel consumption","African colonisation","The fall of the Soviet Union"],"question":"What did the Congress of Vienna meet to discuss in 1815?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Gustave Flaubert","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Three Musketeers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rum ","incorrectAnswers":["Vodka","Whiskey","Brandy"],"question":"Which Alcoholic drink is the main ingredient of the cocktail 'Zombie'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Quiet Riot","incorrectAnswers":["EMF","Toni Basil","Eddy Grant"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1983 with Cum on Feel the Noize?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Laurentian Library","incorrectAnswers":["Bibliotheque Nationale","Library of Alexandria","Ulpian Library"],"question":"What is the name of the famous Florentine library where many Renaissance texts are kept?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"3,000 Metres","incorrectAnswers":["10,000 Metres","5,000 Metres","8,000 Metres"],"question":"Over What Distance Is A Steeple Chase Run?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Taco","incorrectAnswers":["Sushi","Ramen","Pho"],"question":"Which of these is a popular dish in Mexico?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Victor Hugo","incorrectAnswers":["Alphonse Daudet","Jules Verne","Miguel de Cervantes"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Man Who Laughs'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1990","1998"],"question":"In which year was The Lion King released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Air Force One","incorrectAnswers":["The Big One","US One","The Reagan Jet"],"question":"What is the name of the plane that carried the President of the United States?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Tlatoani","incorrectAnswers":["The Coatlicu","The Mesoat","The Chief"],"question":"What was the term used for the Aztec ruler?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Zen and","incorrectAnswers":["Love and","God and","Oil and"],"question":"What two words precede \"The Art of Motorcycle Maintenance\" in the title of Robert Pirsig's 1974 book?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Hornets","incorrectAnswers":["The Blues","The Hatters","Cottagers"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Watford?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Scorpio","incorrectAnswers":["Aries","Gemini","Cancer"],"question":"If you were born on Halloween, what star sign would you be","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dream of the Red Chamber","incorrectAnswers":["Germinal","Madame Bovary","The Decameron"],"question":"In which book does 'Wang Xifeng' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dances With Wolves","incorrectAnswers":["Total Recall","Edward Scissorhands","Pretty Woman"],"question":"Name The 1990 Movie Which Won John Barry An Oscar For Best Film Score","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jimi Hendrix Experience","incorrectAnswers":["Poison","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which English-American psychedelic rock band released the song 'Purple Haze'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Qing","incorrectAnswers":["Ming","Tan","Han"],"question":"What Chinese dynasty was overthrown in 1912?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Snickersnee","incorrectAnswers":["Curmudgeon","Xertz","Cattywampus"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'to engage in cut-and-thrust fighting with knives'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Maniac","incorrectAnswers":["Convoy","Just a Friend","Tainted Love"],"question":"What song did Michael Sembello have a hit with in 1983?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"To victory","incorrectAnswers":["In good faith","Seize the day","Be vindictive"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Ad victoriam' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crocodile","incorrectAnswers":["Kangaroo","Cow","Goliath Spider"],"question":"The __________ does not chew its food, but swallows it whole.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The claustrophobic world of a WWII German U-boat.","incorrectAnswers":["A former Roman General seeks revenge against the emperor who murdered his family.","When two girls move to the country, they have adventures with the forest spirits who live nearby.","Prisoners of war plan to escape from a German camp during World War II."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Das Boot?","difficulty":"medium"},